Captioning Provided By:
MTV Networks
字幕提供者：
MTV网络
Are ya ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
Kids: Aye, aye, Captain.
孩子们：是的，是的，队长。
I can't  hear  you.
我听不到你说话。
Kids:   Aye, aye,
Captain.
孩子们：是啊是啊
队长。
♪ Ohh... ♪
♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
队长：♪ 吸水性的，黄色的
他是多孔的 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ If nautical nonsense
be somethin' you wish ♪
船长：♪ 如果是航海方面的废话
成为你所希望的那样 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
船长：♪ 然后降落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Ready? ♪
队长：♪ 准备好了吗？ ♪
All: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
全部： ♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ SpongeBob
SquarePants ♪
队长：♪ 海绵宝宝
方裤♪
There, there, SpongeBob.
那里，那里，海绵宝宝。
No need to cry.
没必要哭。
Yes, there is, Patrick.
是的，有，帕特里克。
Sandy's been gone
for two whole days.
桑迪已经走了
整整两天。
Two whole days?
整整两天？
Oh, why'd she have to go to that
science convention in Tejas?
哦，为什么她必须去那个地方
科学大会在光辉号举行？
Tejas.
特哈斯。
She won't be back
for one more hour
她不会回来了
再过一小时
26 minutes and 47 seconds.
26分47秒。
Oh, 47 seconds...
哦，47秒...
I miss Sandy so much.
我非常想念桑迪。
Her tentacles, the way
she plays clarinet.
她的触手，方式
她吹单簧管。
Her massive nose.
她的大鼻子。
Patrick, that's Squidward.
帕特里克，那是章鱼哥。
He's not gone, he's right here.
他没有离开，他就在这里。
No, I'm not.
不，我不是。
I sure do miss that squirrel.
我确实很想念那只松鼠。
Her karate chopping.
她的空手道劈砍。
That 10-gallon glass
dome over her dome.
那个10加仑的玻璃杯
圆顶在她的圆顶之上。
And who can forget
those buck teeth?
谁能忘记
那些龅牙？
After Sandy gets back
桑迪回来后
we're gonna let her know
how much we miss her.
我们会让她知道
我们多么想念她。
Is Sandy the one
I call "mom"?
桑迪是那个吗
我叫“妈妈”？
No, Patrick,
that's your mother.
不，帕特里克，
那是你的母亲。
But that does give
me an idea.
但这确实给了
我有一个想法。
We'll throw Sandy the mother
of all welcome home parties.
我们会把妈妈桑迪扔掉
所有欢迎回家聚会。
Patrick, to the tree dome.
帕特里克，去树顶。
Ah.
啊。
Huh?
啊？
We've readied this
place for Sandy's arrival
which should be in about...
我们已经准备好了这个
桑迪到达的地方
应该在大约...
Whoa, right now.
哇，现在。
♪ Welcome home, Sandy ♪
♪ 欢迎回家，桑迪 ♪
♪ You know that we
missed ya ♪
♪ 你知道我们
想念你♪
Man: No!
男：不！
No one wants to hear you sing.
没有人想听你唱歌。
Sorry, SpongeBob, he's got
a fierce no singing policy.
对不起，海绵宝宝，他有
严厉的禁止唱歌政策
That's quite all right,
Miss Cheeks
那就完全没问题了
脸颊小姐
as long as you don't have
a fierce "no partyin'" policy.
只要你没有
严厉的“不参加聚会”政策
First, cake,
then we'll karate chop
首先是蛋糕，
然后我们就空手道砍
and then...
进而...
You two... uh, really know how
to... uh, throw a party.
你们两个……呃，真的知道怎么做
去……呃，举办一个聚会。
I knew it.
我就知道。
You have been itchin'
to see us.
你一直在发痒
来看我们。
Well, something's makin'
my skin crawl.
嗯，有些事情正在发生
我浑身起鸡皮疙瘩。
Maybe a slice of cake
也许是一块蛋糕
will take your mind off
your crawling hide?
会让你忘记
你的爬行隐藏？
Patrick and I made this cake
especially for your return.
帕特里克和我做了这个蛋糕
特别是为了你的归来。
This is gonna taste
so good again.
这会尝到
又这么好。
Dig in, Sandy.
深入挖掘，桑迪。
Uh...
呃...
Looks tasty, SpongeBob.
看起来很好吃，海绵宝宝。
You OK, Sandy?
你还好吗，桑迪？
I'm fine.
我很好。
My skin just hasn't adjusted to
this here underwater air.
我的皮肤还没有适应
这是这里的水下空气。
Uh, hey, Sandy, Sandy?
呃，嘿，桑迪，桑迪？
Surprise, Patrick
and I chipped in
惊喜，帕特里克
我也加入了
and got you a little
somethin' somethin'.
给你一点
某事某事。
Aw, guys, you shouldn't have.
噢，伙计们，你们不应该这样做。
A new itch board...
I mean, a new snow board.
新的止痒板...
我的意思是，一块新的滑雪板。
Boy, I can't wait to scratch
this down chafe mountain.
男孩，我迫不及待地想抓挠
这条查夫山下。
Don't you mean ride
this down scab mountain?
你不是说骑车吗
这山下有痂吗？
Thank you very rawness,
SpongeBob and Pat.
非常感谢你的原始，
海绵宝宝和帕特。
Uh, you're welcome, Sandy.
呃，不客气，桑迪。
Hey, are you still up for
some karate chops?
嘿，你还在等吗
一些空手道排骨？
Rashy sore... I mean, sure.
皮疹疼痛……我的意思是，当然。
You ready?
你准备好了吗？
And how about now?
那么现在呢？
You ready?
你准备好了吗？
Creeping critters, feels like
something's bitin' me.
爬行的小动物，感觉就像
有东西在咬我。
I've got a flea?
我身上有跳蚤？
Well, I ain't gonna take
that without a fight.
好吧，我不会接受
不战而屈人之兵。
Hi-ya!
嗨呀！
I'll get you, hya, hya, hya!
我会抓住你的，嘿，嘿，嘿！
Rrr...
呃……
SpongeBob, ah...
海绵宝宝啊……
My suitcase, hurry.
我的行李箱，快点。
I'm ashamed to say this,
SpongeBob
我很羞愧地说这句话
海绵宝宝
but while I was in Texas, I seem
to have picked up a flea.
但当我在德克萨斯州时，我似乎
捡到一只跳蚤。
What's a flea?
什么是跳蚤？
A flea is a dastardly little
vermin that bites us air
breathers.
跳蚤是一个卑鄙的小东西
咬我们空气的害虫
呼吸者。
But this here flea collar will
send the critter a-runnin'.
但这里的这个除跳蚤项圈会
让小动物逃跑。
He tickles.
他很痒。
Oh, this isn't so bad-
哦，这并没有那么糟糕-
Ow... He bit me.
噢……他咬了我。
Got anymore of those fancy
collars, Sandy?
不再有那些奇特的东西了
项圈，桑迪？
No, but you can use
this one right quick.
不，但你可以使用
这个很快。
Connect the dots.
把这些点连起来。
I drawed a horsie.
我画了一匹马。
Ouch, why does this
flea keep biting me?
哎呀，为什么会这样
跳蚤老咬我？
'Cause he's hungry.
因为他饿了。
When a flea bites ya
当跳蚤咬你时
it's cause he's suckin' up
your blood for nutrition.
这是因为他很糟糕
你的血液的营养。
I've been bitten
by a vampire flea.
我被咬了
由吸血跳蚤引起。
No...!
不...！
I'm going to turn
into a vampire now.
我要转身
现在变成吸血鬼了。
It's already happening.
这已经发生了。
Ah, ah, ah!
啊啊啊！
Pfft...
噗……
Ya-da-da-da-da.
呀呀呀呀呀呀呀。
Patrick, there ain't no such
thing as vampires.
帕特里克，没有这样的
像吸血鬼一样的东西。
Yah, doesn't matter.
嗯，没关系。
Oh, this itch is killing me.
哦，这痒痒得要我的命了。
Nyah... Oh!
尼亚...哦！
Ah...
Give me that!
啊...
给我那个！
Whew.
呼。
Nyah... Oh.
尼亚...哦。
Sandy, please, help me!
桑迪，请帮帮我！
I need this!
我需要这个！
I need it more!
我更需要它！
Eee!
哎呀！
Enough, I will not take
this anymore.
够了，我不会接受
不再这样了。
What ya gonna do now, punks?
现在你们要做什么，朋克们？
Looky, it worked! Whew!
看，成功了！哇！
I'm glad that's over.
我很高兴一切都结束了。
Um, is that what
"over" looks like?
嗯，是这样吗
“结束”是什么样子？
Sandy: Tarnation, they're
multiplying like mad.
桑迪：塔南，他们是
疯狂地繁殖。
Run!
跑步！
OK.
好的。
Oh.
哦。
Huh.
呵呵。
Hey.
嘿。
Y'all got the aim of a
cross-eyed armadillo.
你们都有一个目标
斗鸡眼犰狳。
Ah...!
啊...！
Run again!
再跑！
OK.
好的。
Unh.
呃。
Ah.
啊。
Ah!
啊!
Uh, thanks for having us, Sandy,
but we gotta go.
呃，谢谢你邀请我们，桑迪，
但我们得走了。
Yeah, good to see ya.
是的，很高兴见到你。
Ah!
啊!
: Help, help!
: 救命，救命！
Just ignore them, Squidward
忽略他们吧，章鱼哥
and continue your power walk.
并继续你的力量行走。
Heel toe, heel toe,
heel toe, heel toe.
跟趾，跟趾，
跟趾，跟趾。
Sandy: Back off!
桑迪：退后！
Sandy, oh, no!
桑迪，哦，不！
Are you OK?
你还好吗？
Them varmints is tough.
他们这些恶鼠很难对付。
They're from Texas.
他们来自德克萨斯州。
Whew.
呼。
It's gonna be all right,
we will help you.
一切都会好起来的
我们会帮助你。
OK, you know what?
好吧，你知道吗？
None of this would have
happened if you didn't come back
with your infestation.
这一切都不会有
如果你没有回来就发生了
随着你的侵扰。
All you've brought us is fleas
你给我们带来的只是跳蚤
and trouble and pain and itching
还有麻烦、疼痛和瘙痒
and a rash and pain
and fleas
以及皮疹和疼痛
和跳蚤
and itching and pain.
以及瘙痒和疼痛。
So much pain!
太痛苦了！
So much pain.
太痛苦了。
And as for you...
而至于你...
If you hadn't thrown this party,
we wouldn't be in this mess.
如果你没有举办这个聚会
我们不会陷入这种混乱之中。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
You had as much to do
with this party as I did.
你有那么多事要做
像我一样参加这个聚会。
You call this a party?
你管这叫聚会？
I'm beginning to question
our friendship.
我开始质疑
我们的友谊。
Stop smudging my helmet!
别弄脏我的头盔了！
Oh, I got half a mind, buddy.
哦，我有点不明白，伙计。
Will you two men stop
yelling at each other?
你们两个能停下来吗
互相大喊大叫？
What does that prove?
这证明了什么？
If we're gonna get out of this,
we gotta work together.
如果我们要摆脱这一切
我们必须一起努力。
You're right.
你说得对。
I have an idea.
我有一个主意。
SpongeBob, you get
on Sandy's shoulders.
海绵宝宝，你得到了
在桑迪的肩膀上。
Uh-huh, good.
嗯嗯，很好。
Now...   I'll get
on top of you.
现在...我会得到
在你上面。
Unh, ah.
呃，啊。
Oh, much better.
哦，好多了。
Doh!
哎哟！
I do not play games.
我不玩游戏。
Quick, get in the tree house.
快点，进树屋吧。
It's the only safe place left.
这是唯一剩下的安全地方了。
We should be protected here.
我们应该在这里受到保护。
Hold on.
坚持，稍等。
Is this how we're going
to spend the rest
of our lives?
这就是我们要走的路吗
去度过剩下的时间
我们的生活？
Living in fleas
instead of water?
生活在跳蚤中
而不是水？
SpongeBob, that's
it... water!
海绵宝宝，就是
它……水！
Ha, hi-ya!
哈，嗨！
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha.
哈哈哈哈。
Ya.
是啊。
Water!
水！
: It sure is good
to have you back, Sandy.
: 确实不错
让你回来，桑迪。
Wha, wha... What happened?
什、什……发生什么事了？
Where am I?
我在哪里？
Oh, yeah,
the party.
哦，是的，
聚会。
I must've passed out in
SpongeBob's kitchen...
我一定是昏过去了
海绵宝宝的厨房...
On the ceiling.
在天花板上。
Oof... Oof!
噢……噢！
See, SpongeBob?
看到了吗，海绵宝宝？
I told you we shouldn't
stay up past 8:30.
我告诉过你我们不应该
熬夜超过8点30分。
Things get real crazy
after 8:30.
事情变得非常疯狂
8:30之后。
Would you like another spot
of tea, Ms. Nibsy?
您想要另一个地方吗
尼布西女士，要喝茶吗？
Oh, you would?
哦，你会吗？
Whoo... Chamomile,
chamomile, chamomile!
哇...洋甘菊，
洋甘菊，洋甘菊！
Oh, she really knows how to
pound 'em down, huh, SpongeBob?
哦，她真的知道怎么做
把他们打倒，嗯，海绵宝宝？
SpongeBob... SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝...海绵宝宝？
Sponge...
海绵...
That's a good-lookin' donut.
这是一个好看的甜甜圈。
Wow.
哇。
Oof... Ow!
噢……噢！
What the?
什么？
This donut's connected
to SpongeBob.
这个甜甜圈已连接
海绵宝宝。
Oh...
哦...
It worked.
它起作用了。
A beautiful specimen
of donut-hood.
一个美丽的标本
甜甜圈罩。
A donut this nice deserves to be
served on fine China.
这么好的甜甜圈值得拥有
服务于美好的中国。
The good plate.
好盘。
Don't worry, donut.
别担心，甜甜圈。
No longer will you suffer
the indignity of sub-par
dining wear.
你将不再受苦
低于标准的侮辱
餐饮服。
I don't think I've ever seen
a donut this nice before.
我想我从来没有见过
以前吃过这么好的甜甜圈。
Except maybe that donut
SpongeBob showed me last night.
也许除了那个甜甜圈
海绵宝宝昨晚给我看了。
A donut this nice could
really make a guy happy.
这么好的甜甜圈可以
真的让一个人开心。
Uh...
呃...
This is SpongeBob's delicious...
这是海绵宝宝的美味...
Wai...
哇...
I 'an't eat 'is 'onut.
我“不吃”是“onut”。
It's SpongeBob's.
这是海绵宝宝的。
Go on and eat it.
继续吃吧。
What are you waitin' for?
你还在等什么？
Don't do it,
it's SpongeBob's donut.
别这样做，
这是海绵宝宝的甜甜圈。
Don't listen to him, he's
covered with sprinkles.
别听他的，他是
覆盖着洒水。
I hate conflict.
我讨厌冲突。
It couldn't get any
easier than this.
它无法得到任何
比这更容易。
Just hook a chain to it
只需将链条挂在上面即可
pop it in your mouth
把它放进嘴里
and then when your
sponge friend wants it back
然后当你的
海绵朋友想要回来
just yank it out.
把它拉出来。
I hate to admit it,
but that's a great idea.
我不愿意承认，
但这是个好主意。
Mmm... Ah...
嗯……啊……
And now...
而现在...
SpongeBob's donut,
I ate it!
海绵宝宝的甜甜圈，
我吃了它！
I've gotta sneak this back into
SpongeBob's house before he...
我得把它偷偷带回来
海绵宝宝之前的家...
Hello?
你好？
SpongeBob  :
Hey, Patrick.
海绵宝宝：
嘿，帕特里克。
Ah!
啊!
That was some
party last night, huh, buddy?
那是一些
昨晚的聚会，嗯，伙计？
Ah!
啊!
"Ah!"
“啊！”
Lucky for us, I videotaped
the whole party
我们很幸运，我录了视频
整个聚会
so we can relive it over
and over and over again.
这样我们就可以重温它
一遍又一遍。
Ah, don't watch that tape!
啊，别看那盘录像带！
I'm waiting to watch
it with you, sillyfish.
我等着看
和你一起吧，傻鱼。
I'll be right over.
我马上过去。
Sheesh, Patrick's so excited
谢什，帕特里克太兴奋了
I better not keep him waiting.
我最好别让他等了。
Oh no...
哦不...
That video will show me
stealing SpongeBob's donut.
那个视频会告诉我
偷海绵宝宝的甜甜圈。
Uh-oh, uh-oh, uh-oh,
eee, eee!
呃-哦，呃-哦，呃-哦，
诶诶诶！
I gotta hide this thing.
我得把这件事藏起来。
Phew.
唷。
Oh.
哦。
Hey Patrick, I-
嘿帕特里克，我-
donut!
油炸圈饼！
You monster.
你这个怪物。
You monster!
你这个怪物！
Nothing goes with a video
like toast.
视频没有任何内容
像吐司。
Let's pop
some toast in the toaster
让我们流行吧
烤面包机里放一些吐司
and watch this bad boy.
看看这个坏男孩。
Ow, ow, hot, hot, ow!
呜呜呜，好热啊好热啊！
Get out of the way, Patrick,
I gotta go.
帕特里克，让开，
我得走了。
The attic.
阁楼。
Wait, I don't have an attic.
等等，我没有阁楼。
Oh...
哦...
Oh... Ooh, I know.
哦...哦，我知道了。
The attic.
阁楼。
Ah!
啊!
Hey, Patrick.
嘿，帕特里克。
H-Hey, SpongeBob.
嘿嘿，海绵宝宝。
Are you ready to...
你准备好了吗...
I don't have anything behind my
back, so don't look there.
我的背后没有任何东西
回来了，所以不要看那里。
OK, no problem.
好的，没问题。
Ready to see this?
准备好看看这个了吗？
The official
testament of how heartily
we party... hardy?
官方
证明多么衷心
我们聚会……坚强吗？
No!
不！
I took it, SpongeBob.
我拿走了，海绵宝宝。
I took your donut.
我拿走了你的甜甜圈。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
Oh, Patrick, you really need
to see this video.
哦，帕特里克，你真的需要
观看此视频。
I wanna give you this,
because you're my buddy
我想给你这个
因为你是我的朋友
and a donut this nice
还有这么好的甜甜圈
could really make
a guy happy.
真的可以让
一个快乐的人。
You mean... This is mine?
你的意思是……这是我的？
Of course, it  was  your birthday.
当然，那天是你的生日。
When?
什么时候？
Last night, silly.
昨晚，傻了。
Oh, thanks, buddy.
哦，谢谢，伙计。
Wanna share it?
想分享吗？
Sure, pal.
当然，朋友。
Yum, Yum, Yum...
嗯，嗯，嗯……
Pretty good, huh?
相当不错吧？
Well, good night folks,
come again.
嗯，大家晚安，
再来吧。
Thought those deadbeats would
never leave.
以为那些赖账者会
永远不要离开。
Closin' time,
SpongeBob.
关门时间到了，
海绵宝宝。
There ya go, little buddy.
就这样吧，小伙子。
Now everybody's all clean
and ready for beddy-bye.
现在大家都干净了
准备睡觉了。
Time to pack it in,
SpongeBah...!
是时候打包了，
海绵呸……！
All ready, Mr. Krabs.
一切准备就绪，蟹老板。
Just gotta clock out and...
只需要打卡下班然后...
SpongeBob, what's
the meaning of this?
海绵宝宝，什么
这是什么意思？
Spot, spot, spot!
现货，现货，现货！
That's right, a spot.
没错，就是一个地方。
You know the rule.
你知道规则。
Nobody leaves work till...
没有人离开工作直到...
...Till everything's
ship-shape, sir.
...直到一切都结束
船形，先生。
Don't worry, Mr. Krabs
别担心，蟹老板
I'll get this plate
cleaned up in a jiffy.
我去拿这个盘子
一下子就清理干净了。
Oh, and uh, lock up
when you're done.
哦，呃，锁起来
当你完成时。
Lock up?
Wait, Mr. Krabs.
锁？
等等，蟹老板。
Don't you remember what
happened last time you
left me here alone?
你不记得什么了吗
上次发生在你身上
把我一个人留在这里？
Should have never left you alone
不应该让你独自一人
with a lit blow torch
and me roller skates.
用点燃的喷灯
我和溜冰鞋。
But, since I've removed
all the welding equipment
from the premises
但是，既然我已经删除了
所有焊接设备
从该处所
there's no-ho-ho chance of that
happenin' again, right?
没有那个机会
又发生了，对吧？
Now get to work.
现在开始工作吧。
La la, la la la la la.
啦啦，啦啦啦啦。
Mmm, mmm, mmm.
嗯，嗯，嗯。
Oh, you're a tough little guy,
aren't ya?
哦，你是个坚强的小家伙，
不是吗？
Mmm, mmm, mmm.
嗯，嗯，嗯。
This means war.
这意味着战争。
Ah...!
啊...！
Wait here, please.
请在这里等一下。
Say good night, dried-on filth.
说晚安，干涸的污物。
Ready, aim, fire!
准备，瞄准，开火！
That is the last straw!
那是最后一根稻草！
And I want you to remember...
我希望你记住...
: You made me
do this.
: 是你成就了我
做这个。
Argh!
啊！
I got to finish this.
我必须完成这件事。
I am afraid this is
the last time we'll be meeting
like this, my friend.
恐怕这是
我们最后一次见面
就像这样，我的朋友。
Allow me to introduce you to...
请允许我向您介绍...
The Spot-Master 6000.
Spot-Master 6000。
现货大师6000。
Notice, the microwave-powered
laser particle beam.
注意，微波供电的
激光粒子束。
Notice, the laser-guided high
pressure water cannon.
请注意，激光制导高
压力水炮。
And notice, the little surprise
I installed just for you.
请注意，这个小惊喜
我专门为你安装的。
A specially-woven metal alloy
特殊编织的金属合金
ingeniously combined with state
of the art cleansing materials.
与国家巧妙结合
艺术清洁材料。
I call it...
steel wool.
我称之为...
钢丝绒。
And it comes with... A laser!
它配备了...激光！
Any last words?
最后还有什么话要说吗？
Mmm, I thought not.
嗯，我以为不是。
Power up.
通电。
Water cannon on.
水枪开。
No effect.
没有效果。
Steel wool laser... On!
钢丝绒激光...开启！
Hmmm, strange vortex
in the west.
嗯嗯，奇怪的漩涡
在西方。
Well, it's probably nothing
to do with SpongeBob.
嗯，可能没什么
与海绵宝宝有关。
OK, you asked for it.
好吧，你自找的。
It may end life as we know it
正如我们所知，它可能会结束生命
but I am crossing the beams.
但我正在跨越横梁。
More power!
更多力量！
Spontaneous molecular
distortion, hmm?
自发分子
失真，嗯？
I guess I better go see
what the lad's up to.
我想我最好去看看
这小伙子在做什么。
More power!
更多力量！
Oh boy, this doesn't
look good.
哦，孩子，这不是
看起来不错。
More power!
更多力量！
Let's see what he's done
this time.
让我们看看他做了什么
这次。
Maximum power!
最大功率！
Ah...!
啊...！
Oh, this time,
ya done it, boy.
哦，这一次，
你做到了，孩子。
What do you got
to say for yourself?
你有什么
为自己说？
The platter's all
clean, Mr. Krabs.
拼盘就全了
干净，蟹老板。
Oh, I'll clean your platter!
哦，我来清理你的盘子！
Come here, you.
过来吧，你。